<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Excretion and Homeostasis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/markdown_syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/markdown_syntax/</guid>
      <description>Skin The skin is used to excrete urea, excess water, salts, ammonia. Functions of the skin. Protection of the underlying tissues from entry of microorganisms, physical damage and ultra violet rays from the sun. Regulation of body temperature/thermoregulation. Excretion. Reception of stimuli of heat, cold, pain, touch and pressure. 5. Synthesis of vitamin D. Storage of fats.&#xA;ADAPTATION TO FUNCTION OF DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE SKIN The skin consists of two main layers: epidermis and dermis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kidney</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/kidney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/categories/kidney/</guid>
      <description>KIDNEY. It is used to excrete urea, uric acid, excess water, salts. It performs the following functions:&#xA;Excretion Osmoregulation (regulation of water and ionic content in blood) Regulation of pH of blood and tissue fluid. A mammal has a pair of kidneys located in the abdominal cavity. They are bean-shaped and red in colour. The adrenal glands are located above each kidney which secrete hormones. Parts of a kidney. Hilum- it is a depression located on the concave side of the kidney through which the renal artery enters to supply blood from the heart containing oxygen, nutrients and urea and renal vein which removes blood from kidney from the kidney to the heart containing carbon (IV) oxide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nephron</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nephron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tags/nephron/</guid>
      <description>THE NEPHRON. This is the basic functional unit of the kidney. Each kidney contains about 5 million nephrons. Parts of the nephron.&#xA;Afferent arteriole- brings blood to the nephron from the renal artery.&#xA;Efferent arteriole - takes blood away from the nephron to the renal vein.&#xA;Bowman&amp;rsquo;s capsule- cavity which encloses the glomerulus.&#xA;Glomerulus (Plural- glomeruli) - a network of capillaries enclosed by Bowman’s capsule.&#xA;Proximal convoluted tubule- it is coiled and extends into Loop of Henle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/categories/skin/</guid>
      <description>Skin The skin is used to excrete urea, excess water, salts, ammonia. Functions of the skin. Protection of the underlying tissues from entry of microorganisms, physical damage and ultra violet rays from the sun. Regulation of body temperature/thermoregulation. Excretion. Reception of stimuli of heat, cold, pain, touch and pressure. 5. Synthesis of vitamin D. Storage of fats.&#xA;ADAPTATION TO FUNCTION OF DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE SKIN The skin consists of two main layers: epidermis and dermis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/studyquestions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tags/studyquestions/</guid>
      <description>Study question State one homeostatic role of the human skin.  Thermoregulation, osmoregulation, regulation of salts.&#xA;Name three structures of the skin essential for its homeostatic function. Sweat glands. Hair. Erector pili muscle. Blood vessels/ arterioles.. Nerve endings.&#xA;Explain why the amount of sweat increases with increase in temperature. This is because of increase in latent heat of vaporization hence causing evaporation/ vaporization of sweat to cool the body.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
